[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trient tasa Advanced
Training as you all know I already
published 57 YouTube videos covering
beginners intermediate and advanced
level Concepts from couple of videos
onwards I've started teaching teing you
the real time scenarios where you might
encounter with different types of
obstacles while automating your test
cases how can we solve those obstacles
whenever you automate your test cases by
using trient tasa so this is our
obstacle
16 in terms of real time scenarios and
this is our lesson 58 in terms of
overall trient tasa
training please do subbe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos don't forget to like and share
the video thank you in this lesson I'm
going to teach you a realtime scenario
where you need to solve an
obstacle by interacting with
Windows popup by using window operations
within the standard modules of trient
tasa
so let us see what is the obstacle that
we need to solve
for so here is the
obstacle the name of the obstacle is
popup windows and it is categorized as
easy let us go for
it what is the obstacle in order to
complete this obstacle you need to click
the button labeled click
me and close the new window that is
subsequently opened so let me click on
this click me Button as soon as you
click on click me button it opens a
window popup so this window popup title
contains Tri sentes so we need to review
this window popup and close the popup so
you solve this automation problem so
that is our obstacle that we need to
solve so now let us go to trien
tasa as usual we're going to scan all
the objects of this particular obstacle
under folder obstacles so this is our
module right right
click
scan
application so this is our application
let's select the application click on
scan
so for this obstacle to solve we need
the button click me right let us select
the button click me this is our button
and what about the popup window that is
appearing so we need not to scan the
windows po
popup why because we are going to handle
the windows popup by using Windows
operation that comes along with the
standard modules of trient toas so
whenever you purchase a license in
trient TSA so you're going to get the
standard modules of TSA along with the
license so you can use the standard
modules and select
window operations to operate the window
in different ways okay so that's why I'm
going to add click me button right it is
uniquely identifying let's see this
click me button is getting a identified
uniquely right and then let us name this
module with the name of your obstacle
copy
this and here name the module with the
obstacle name rename the module and now
let's save all
the objects and the
module so let us close the
xcan so let's go back to trient tasa so
this is the latest module that we
scanned double click on this you can see
here click me button we already captured
now let us go to the left section which
is a test case section
okay so right click on this sorry so we
are creating all the test cases under
folder test case folder called obstacle
double click on this so these are all
the test cases that we automated for our
previous 15 obstacles so I would
recommend you guys to visit my previous
15 obstacle videos you can find the
playlist in the description okay right
click on this
particular test case folder and create a
new test
case name this test case with the name
of your
obstacle and then double click on this
test case now let us automate the test
case for
that so we need to drag this module onto
your test case to complete our
automation let's drag this module and
drop on to the test case that we created
okay now expand this what is our first
first action that we need to perform so
we need to click on this
button so here I'm going to provide the
value as
click okay and then your action mode is
input once that is done so as soon as
you click you will get a popup so how
can we handle this popup for that let's
go back to our trient Taska and let me
bring these modules
here so here if you scroll
up
whenever you purchase a license of
trient tasa you are going to get these
standard modules expand the standard
modules go to tbox automation tools and
then within this you will have basic
Windows
operations and here is tbox window
operation so this is the module standard
module that we are going to use to
handle the popup windows so basically
window based popups we can handle by
using tbox window operations standard
module under basic Windows operations so
what I'm going to do I'm going to drag
this standard module tbox window
operation and drop onto test
case
now let us expand this
step and here you can see the operation
that we now here we can see the
operations that are available for any
window in tbox what are the operations
you can see here bring to front close
maximize
minimize normal wait on
close wait on open resize move to Center
verify window exist so these are all the
different operations that are available
for your window popups so now first we
need to provide the caption what is the
caption of so what is the caption of the
what is the caption of the window let's
go back here you can see here the window
caption
is trient is atate trient is so what I'm
going to do I'm going
to use the regular expression to read
this window title I can see here it has
a tricentis
as instring right let's go go back to
our prent tasa what I'm going to do I'm
going to use the regular expression star
which is a regular expression any string
and then
tricentis and then again regular
expression star so
here any string can be existing before
trient and then after this any string
can be exist after
trient so now let us come to
operation so first I would like to close
the popup window but if I specify close
the pop-up window here what happens
right sometimes to open this popup
window it takes time let us click on
this one see as soon as I click
immediately it is not loading the popup
see it's taking some time and then it is
loading the popup so that means it's
going to throw an error message if you
directly close the popup
because it cannot identify the popup it
is still loading so that's why I would
like to use another operation before I
close it what is that wait on open what
it does it's going to wait for the popup
with title TR with title tric centes to
open so it waits for the popup to be
open first and then you can see I want
to perform close operation within the
same test step by using the operation
see as soon as I enter operation it is
recreating the
operation module so whenever you enter
the operation immediately it creates
another operation module right so I'm
waiting for the popup to be open and
then I'm closing the popup so now let us
update the work state as
completed and then
save the test
case and let me run this particular test
case so before I run this particular
test case if you see here you see here
the main
obstacle module right whatever we
scanned that also has trienes in the
page title that's why if you specify
trienes it's going to close this
particular web page instead of closing
the windows windows popup so that's why
what I'm going to do here in Windows
popup I can see at the rate at the rate
T I can see at theate tric sentence
right so I would like to take that as my
caption so let's go back to our
tricentis tasa let us change this as at
the rate
tricentis right and then save this now
let us run this particular test case
right click and run
see it is clicking on button and then it
waits for the popup to load see it
waited and it closed so you solve this
automation problem let me run this
particular test case one more time let's
go back here close this right click and
run in scratchbook
[Music]
so you solve the automation
problem you can see all the test steps
are
passed in the test results let's close
this rash book this is how you can
handle the window operations so this is
how you can handle the window popups by
using tbox window operation within the
standard modules of tric sentence if you
have any queries leave your queries in
the comment box I'll try to respond to
your
queries hope you all understand the
concept of resolving the obstacle where
you need to interact with window popup
and how can we use window operations
within your standard modules of trient
tasa please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos don't forget to like and share
the video thank you
[Music]